Guillermo Peralta Scura

Front-end Web Developer

Detail-oriented web developer with more than 7 years of experience in software engineering. Accessibility and fast initial page rendering are my main areas of focus. I enjoy working as part of a team and tackling interesting challenges.

Asunción, Paraguay)
+595982742811	
gperaltascura@gmail.com	<
<u>/voluntadpear</u>	_
/guillermo-peralta-scura	1
<u>@voluntadpear</u>	Ì
https://goshi.dev	\bigoplus

WORK EXPERIENCE

PSPDFKit GmbH, Vienna, Austria (Remote) — Web Engineer SEPTEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Led the development of several features as part of the <u>PSPDFKit</u> for <u>Web PDF editor</u> offering of the company, with React, TypeScript, Redux, Jest, React Testing Library, Playwright.
- Headed the development of the new demo site for the SDK with Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Playwright, and Storybook.
- Handled direct support via e-mail and calls with customers to debug their integrations and helped them through our offering.
- Wrote several technical blog posts for the company. [1] [2] [3]

Sulvo, Las Vegas, NV (Remote) — Web developer

APRIL 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- Led the progressive migration of the main application from Meteor Blaze to Vue and introduced Jest to the team for Unit and Integration tests.
- Replaced previous web development tooling with a newer one based on Webpack with hot-reloading, debugging support, and code splitting improving both developers' and users' experiences. As well as proposing and adding Sentry for better production errors monitoring.
- Collaborated closely with the UI designer to create outstanding interactions for the end-user.
- Mentored, coached, and assisted with the onboarding of new members of the team easing their way into making effective collaborations and getting comfortable with our team culture.

Codium, Asunción, Paraguay — *Web and mobile developer*JANUARY 2015 - APRIL 2018

•

 Contributed to the development of an open-source collaborative document editor called <u>PeerDoc</u> with Vue for the front-end and Meteor for the back-end.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Elixir

Frameworks/Libraries

React, Redux, Jest, React Testing Library, Next.js, Playwright, Vue, Express, Apollo, Vuex, Redux, AWS Lambda

Databases

MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

EDUCATION

National University of Asunción, Asunción, Paraguay — Computer Engineering 2012 - 2019

LANGUAGES

Spanish (native), English (advanced)

PROJECTS

Vue Choropleth — <u>Source</u> <u>Code on GitHub</u>

Open Source Choropleth Map component for Vue.

Calcular Compras — *Source Code on GitHub*

Vue + TypeScript PWA to estimate shipping costs from the US to Paraguay.